[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast at what age do we learn how to
have better
conversations at what age do we learn to
have better conversations with ourselves
what's up what's up y'all my
recommendation today is going to be in
the form of a book and it's going to be
the book The War of art by Steven
pressfield the war of art by Steven
pressfield uh it's absolutely fantastic
I suggest it for really anybody who's
facing resistance in their life
resistance of any sort of course this
works for creators um but nowadays I
think with this with this fast-paced
world we're all a bit of a Creator in in
many different ways so the war of art by
Steven pressfield if if you want a
10-minute uh Lowdown on the book I'm
sure they have it on YouTube or the app
called blinkist give it a look welcome
to the podcast
enjoy
Max Max Max Max Jake Jake Jake Jake my
brother will you walk me first and
foremost through the spelling and
pronunciation of your last
name
pain p a y n e all
right you got to you got to keep the V
you got to have the V there it's so it's
not Max pain it's Max V pain that it's
crucial tell me about that though we
were talking about aliases before
this well talking about different
different names different stage names
real names M we can expand on all oh do
you want me to like go into my real real
name it's up to you trying to get away
from that yeah that's
a should I need to be focused in on that
sorry sorry my bad that's my bad so max
V pay tell me about this name uh that's
Alias that's that's just the uh the the
Alias that that I decided to go with um
I don't know let's say when did I change
it a year ago two years
ago year and a half two years ago uh it
was it was more of
like I wasn't because I I went by
dopamine uh at least for my as my rap
name okay so let's just let's let's
start just so we have context for
everything uh my name is Max vpay I am a
father from Vancouver Washington I'm
actually technically from Kelo
Washington but I do live in Vancouver
right uh I make hip-hop music I produce
hip-hop music uh I am a videographer I
love to make music videos all types of
videos I have several different projects
I'm working on right now uh I fancy
myself a comedian sometimes so I think I
could be pretty funny uh I've done some
standup comedy in my time uh and
so I do a whole lot of different kind of
things uh with the team halflife
entertainment um but I kind of for a
while I was like known as so dopamine
was the rapper and then Max is you know
the guy who makes the videos and and and
all that other stuff you're funny on
social media all that yeah I try to be
uh it works out sometimes um but I guess
at some point uh a year ago I changed
cuz my my full name all right we're
going to there my real name my full name
is
maim okay so I'm not going to spell that
for you that was what I was trying to TW
you into saying very first and I
apologize to catch you off guard like
that I thought you were going to roll
into it I think like altogether that's
like 37 letters or something like that I
counted when I was younger Wow way too
much way too long of a name but you
wrote that at the top of every paper uh
no no I I do not put my middle name now
that's that's horrible but if you were
to look at my uh my driver's license
what it says on there okay okay uh yeah
but uh I kind of tried to get away from
that a little bit I just wanted to
shorten my name up so I it was more of
like a you know uh just a kind of a
pseudonym because I'm I'm Into You Know
the music but I also I'm really into
like film and movies and things like
that and and I want to like I want to
act so like my before I ever wanted to
be a rapper I wanted to be an actor you
know I wanted you're an allaround
Creator exactly yeah so there's uh for
instance like a Vin Diesel his real name
is Mark Vincent you know all right I
feel like I forgot about that yeah so
it's it's something it's kind of the
same thing there where I was just like
let me just kind of shorten up the name
make it a little bit like more pleasing
to look at a lot quicker to say because
you know even Max PUK is like that's
that's a mouthful you know and so
anybody who sees the name like the first
question is how the how do you pronounce
that right like how do you say that you
know and I'm like do you want the
Russian pronunciation or do you want the
English it's almost a waste of your time
at this point it's like doesn't matter
my name is this it's just is Bob let's
get on with our conversation yeah so I
just I just decided to go with a quick
simple easy name Max V pay I think uh I
think it works it it works really nicely
and then as of you know last year end of
last year beginning of this year uh I
I'm no longer going by dopamine and I
never even like I never announced that
to anybody or anything like that you
know I didn't think people cared that
much is there is there like a world
where we should announce it quote
unquote isn't that like kind of weird
you feel like want me to tell everybody
but also what it's kind of people do you
know and it's weird with like local
rappers when they try to make these
really huge ass announcements when it's
like okay like you're not really popular
enough for anybody to actually give that
much of a [__] you know and they kind of
got to make like a whole huge big deal
out of it well I mean that's that comes
with the being an artist being a
musician nowadays it means that you uh
you have album art and you have teasers
and you have like all these things like
everybody has their own level of like
their release that they feel they need
to do now you know I feel like that
spans pretty broad um so when it comes
to aliases so for a long time so how we
know each other um I mean I feel like we
know each other just through friends and
friends and Facebook of of regular life
names but we've also worked together
multiple times um I've djed for just you
know played your instrumentals at a few
shows and and hung out with you guys and
thank you for your involvement in those
shows man you uh you're a great DJ our
favorite one to work with so far yeah
thanks man I appreciate working with you
guys I just I mean hanging out with you
guys is great uh I I can't wait for the
future I'm sure we're going to be
getting in on some music together here
soon we' got some things to talk about
of course but um so at that time though
I knew you more as as dopamine as your
rap Alias um can you can you start me
from your the beginning of your rap
world when you first let let's say how
old were you when you first heard your
first rap song that you liked and and
when did you start doing your own Okay
so
uh when I first heard rap music I did
not like rap music you remember what it
was I had no idea what it was but I like
the way I described it and I remember
being probably like seven years old or
something like that but like hearing
something and then I was talking to
somebody and I was like I don't like
that music where it sounds like they're
talking you know like that's that's just
that's how I could because for me like
um I've always been more influenced by
like rock music music you know and and
and things like that like uh that that
was so thing things where you can like
really just kind of feel the emotion and
the Cadence and the melody and what not
like for me that was something that
always drew me to so when I hear like
just even as a kid uh you know back when
I used to go to church you know there's
c i remember there's like certain songs
that uh that they' sing and just because
of the Cadence like I was locked in i'
would be getting goosebumps you know and
you're being told as a kid you're
getting the Holy Spirit the Goosebumps
of the Holy Spirit and I'm like I'm
captivated by the way that they're
singing it you know and it just like and
I also remember uh they we'd have like a
project like uh one of those old school
projectors that you use at school but
they had it on my church where they put
the lyrics of the songs that you're sing
was like an Elmo with the remember those
where they WR yeah you write on it yeah
exactly but they like they got these
printed and at the time that was like
technology at its finest you yeah
exactly uh and I remember my favorite
songs were the songs where the words
rhymed at the end of each line like so
as a kid so I didn't know what that was
but I just know I'm like it sounds weird
when they're singing those songs but
they're not rhyming in them like that I
didn't like that that was weird to me
you know uh and then I pull this thing a
little bit closer buddy yeah I'm sorry
my bad I'm G get in go talk to the front
of it and more less the
top I'll explain later yeah I put the
new cap anyway so I didn't like rap
music when I first heard it as a kid and
then I think the first time I heard
actually no no no no this is a lie
because I remember when I first heard
Eminem
uh I thought Eminem sounded like cuz I
heard like I heard I'd heard other
rappers you know when it's like a you
know an African-American rapper they're
like you know they got the the Bassy
Voice or whatever and then Eminem came
out and I was like this sounds like a I
was like it sounds like a dude with
allergies or like a girl so I thought it
was funny you know uh and then I
remember like Lose Yourself came out and
I thought that was like so cool uh I
thought it was awesome and I remember me
and Ryan uh Ryan Reed uh who is in
halflife entertainment with me um he we
were friends since like first grade you
know so we go we go way back but I
remember being uh in in highcap and he
was there too and I brought up this song
Lose Yourself by Eminem I was like have
you heard that or and he was like he was
like sorry he was like dude Eminem sucks
like that's that song's whack whatever
and it so it kind of like shut me down
and I was like yeah I guess swag you
know like so you're like a kid it's like
you're influence really easily so it's
like yeah Dam whatever so I kind of like
moved off from it but in that time uh I
started writing lyrics uh I started
writing poetry when I was nine years old
uh I wrote my first poem as a 9-year-old
and then uh I started writing like songs
when I was 11 and at the time I wanted
to start a Christian rock band epic yeah
dude I was like yeah is that what was
called RTC road to
Christ that's so Cy it's probably used
now honestly somebody else took it by
now from 11 years old to probably about
13 I know I wrote something like 80
songs for this Christian rock group and
like these were like I had books full of
lyrics and stuff like that so I was
already writing like songs you remember
would you like just go to your room like
would you and your brother hang out and
make him together or no he he liked he
liked guitar so I mean a lot of a lot of
this like he was supposed to be the
guitarist in this band you know uh but a
lot of this band was just me writing
songs and yeah I'd be doing a lot of it
by myself I remember especially like as
a kid there'd be a lot of nights where
we're watching movies as like a family
and [__] like that and while they're
watching the movie I'm like all right
whatever I'm gonna go downstairs and I'd
go downstairs and I'd either I remember
I had my parents got me like got us this
boom box and it had like a tape player
that you could record music with and
stuff like that so uh I would like one
on either side was it remember there was
like oh yeah uh no it was newer than
that it was it was like it was newer
than so it's like this one and you could
record things off of the radio onto a
cassette tape uh so I I would so while
they're watching movies I'd go
downstairs and I would turn on the radio
listen to my favorite and like my
parents my parents only let us listen to
the Christian radio oh but when they
were watching movies I could go to
Z100 right and I was listening to like
Smashmouth in Lincoln Park and [__] like
that at the time right uh but so for me
my fun thing I didn't like watching the
movies I wanted to be downstairs and I
was like recording my favorite songs
because I just really like listening to
the radio whatnot and then it translated
into now I'm just going down stealing
time away so I could be writing in this
little uh red composition book and I
wrote probably 75 or 80 songs uh by the
time I was like 12 or 13 years old uh do
you remember what kind of so so they
were Church related songs were they like
were they related to rap at all would
you say or were they just like getting
some stuff that rhymes out no it was
just it was just kind of R rhyming like
cuz I thought I was going to be a singer
let me sing one real quick I remember
wait wait introduce the man talking real
quick okay uh so over here we have my
younger brother Giannis also known as
kitis uh he is a singer and apparently
he remembers one of the uh Christian
songs I wrote 20 years and 15 years ago
uh yeah hit him he's going to lean in on
the mic we didn't grabb him some
headphones and a mic set up for this so
we just going to lean in
okay you're going to remember this one
the only reason I remember this one was
because uh we sat with ver and she kind
of worked with you on
it the the Jesus it's cold hold us
tonight Jesus it's
cold give us your
life okay I remember yeah I wrote a song
that sounds great dude no I wrote a song
about uh I wrote a song it was about a a
family that was like uh that was poor
and that was not doing well in life
right and so they like they it was it
was a story about a family who like you
know they're living in a house that they
can't afford anymore and their heat got
shut off what not so there was like so
you took rap stories into church words
it wasn't it wasn't even rap it was like
it was all singing well that's like the
rap Vibe of like here's what real life
is about you know you brought that
church I was a child we never had our
heat turned off we never no we never I
was like I want to but I want to R
something about about
about but actually then like at cuz at
the time like you know we were still
doing quite all right and like it wasn't
we weren't doing like horribly in life
until a few years after that because
after that point we had moved to
Vancouver my parents got divorced uh and
then my mom who had like and then my
mother sorry and then my mother who uh
you know
spent 12 years as a stay-at-home mom not
speaking a word of English suddenly had
to take care of three boys by herself
you know uh and so then then we kind of
started doing back and I started get
more of like real life experiences but
at the time I was just a kid and I
wanted something to write about you know
um but I didn't start rapping
until I want to say in seventh grade I
started walking around uh the gym with
my friends just like throwing random
freestyles because I already knew how to
rhyme based on all the songs and stuff
that I'd been writing uh and so I'd be
walking around just throwing really
stupid freestyles and they would just be
like w like that's crazy yeah you know
how homies do yeah exactly you know uh
and so I was like okay well you know
that's fun and so I I I wrote a couple
different really stupid rap songs but it
was um my freshman year of high school
where I recorded my first song that I
wrote uh and it was called we smack
[__] we already talked about we're
going to get the reduct of this we going
when's the next show bro are you going
to open with that yeah I I'm going to
chant it from the crowd until you played
or throw me out speaking speaking of
aliases my first Alias uh was Uncle
sugar because I thought give it to him
Uncle sugar thought I was a I thought I
was a pimp how old were you at Uncle
sugar four 15 clearly okay 15 15 and
that's actually funny because at 17
years old is when I changed it to
dopamine and people got mad at me they
were like why that's so stupid I'm like
because who the [__] is listening to a
white kid named Uncle
sugar right you're like did you not hear
my name right Uncle sugar the first of
the rap songs I was making were like
jokes I was like I'm obviously not
taking this seriously like I thought it
was funny you know and I was like let me
make gangsta music like whatever so I I
didn't take any of it seriously and yeah
it wasn't until I was probably 17 where
I wrote a rap song that was like about
myself about my own life and whatnot and
I was like oh like I could do something
like this that's a way to get some
things out and so that's when I went
into dopin because when I started taking
it seriously that's when I took on
dopamine uh and uh kind of my my my
thoughts behind that one which it's
actually funny the first time I heard
the word dopamine which you know anybody
who doesn't know science and biology
it's a neurotransmitter in your brain
that like gives you the feelings of like
Jo oh you got it right there endorphins
dopamine seros seratonin and oxytocin
that's happiness put together it's
happiness exactly okay so for me many
things the first time I heard the phrase
or the word dopamine it was on a bet
freestyle okay and uh uh Eminem was on
it and it was like most deaf black th
thought in Eminem okay and then Eminem
had this line on like I can't remember
it was like like a Coke fiend opening a
bottle of dopamine like that was the
first time I heard that and I was like
what that's so cool like that o that's a
cool word it's very Snappy with the way
it Rhymes too exactly dopamine is thrown
he had a really cool I mean you know he
just put an album out awesome I'm not
promoting his album sorry uh but anyway
like that was the first time I heard the
word and I thought it was really cool
and then I went and figured out what met
and it was you know it's neurot
transmitter that makes you feel good
promotes feelings of you know makes you
feel good I was like I was like yeah
light bul went off in my head it's like
I make people feel good you know and at
the time it was just saying really
stupid things on like Facebook to make
people laugh you know uh but yeah so I
went with dopamine for several years up
until and the last song I put out as
dopamine was almost fully a year ago
it's called Thrones really cool song uh
but that was the last one I released as
dopamine and then after that point like
it's just I'm kind of veering away from
like you know rap names rap aliases
things like that like I decided on Max
vpay as a as a name for myself and now I
just want that to be across all
platforms you know across my comedy
across my music across my videos across
everything like you're you're going to
it's me you know I I don't need I don't
need different eles like I'm the same
person and I'm doing all these things
and I want to be successful at every
single one of these things so that's
that's the super long version of my name
sorry no no not not super long version
at all that's dude that's the thing long
form podcast is we're not in a rush I
don't have to give you like this like
quick interview [__] like we can just
[__] you can tell me because dude a
lot of the times I notice as someone's
like hey how'd you get the name blah
blah blah or how'd you do d d and I'll
start talking about it and I'm like man
I kind of don't know [__] until I start
blabbing about it like oh yeah that is
kind of how I it forms together you know
as as we get talking about it so dude
you got the ground to talk about it um
so so forming
aliases it's so cool um a lot times I've
had a couple people on here um already
actually probably four or five who have
aliases and we talked about aliases
because I think that it's um people who
are artists it might be like a weird
thing or it might be some sort of like
egocentric thing like you're just trying
to get like different areas but it's
it's not it's it's definitely something
that is is built and easily accessible
in in um in in the way the world works
now like we don't have to car categorize
ourselves into just one thing like if we
have different projects and different
sides of us that represent different
things and we don't want all of them to
run into our normal everyday life
walking around we can kind of create
these little strong holds that seem to
like put it into perspective CU I had I
had one time where I played um I played
a place in town and they put my name on
the billboard as DJ Jake Ryan and I was
like God damn it and I've had that
before at like yeah like little bars and
stuff or they'll put like I've had one
that was DJ konis okay so it it's c h r
o n us but but it was way worse there
was something even worse about it but DJ
chronics I know but it's it does kind of
make you question it's like oh yeah this
whole thing is kind of silly like it's
like I don't feel they need to be a diva
about it but it is nice to funnel our
life
into you
know different areas of ourselves so um
you kind of gave your your rap
background uh but there's a lot of
different sides of you that that I want
to touch on just like you're a very
in-depth person so let's slide into
comedy I I I I uh I did a show uh did
you do only one comedy show with me with
me there or was it two I no I think I
did were you at the September show yeah
the the we were raising money for YWCA
uh at that one and I uh I've I've done
two I've done two at Paris okay okay
then no then no you uh so yeah you were
you were at my very first comedy show
okay I've done I've done two like really
there was one where you did a slideshow
story too though that's the one that
okay yeah then you were at the second
one that was the September one that was
the September one dude yeah I'm sorry
yeah dates but but yes so I saw both of
them and it's and it's it's cool to see
you explore this side and it was pretty
damn funny and I have you on social
medias and you're always super funny on
so social media um you're good at the
interaction too like it's not just like
uh you you're witty too so so meaning
like if someone has something to say
about it in the comments you respond
with the [__] hilarious thing too
like it's just great so it excites me
dude I'm just like like for me at this
point in my life I'm just like if I'm
seeing a dreamer I'm like [__] yeah bro
because I just I just feel like I
understand what you you
know love that about you man I think I
think that's that's so cool and like you
know you you spread a lot of positivity
with that and and because of that what
not so I really appreciate that thank no
doubt dude I I I try to I mean and you
you you spread a lot of laughter um so I
want to dive into that so at what point
when you're you're you're rapping and
you're enjoying life obviously you're
not just like
247 just rapping and writing lyrics
right like you can dive into a little
bit of what your life was like right
here and then how did you transition
into like when do you kind of start
doing comedy in the more recent years
and and what what was the like did
anybody give you permission or did you
just like you know what I want to just
do this thing or can you talk about that
yeah um
comedy that was always there for me I
got I got in trouble once cuz I called
myself a ComEd comian uh and and my
buddy uh Joseph crumb who was also who
was more of a comedian than I am uh he
actually does a lot of shows and whatnot
but I think I have him on Facebook he
checked me he checked me one time
because he was like he was like you know
he's like if you go around calling
yourself a comedian that's going to piss
people off I'm like why he's like you
haven't done any shows I'm like I know
but I'm funny
like I figured that's all that I needed
to qualify you know uh but that was uh
so comedy was kind of like always around
it was just a natural thing I just
always enjoyed making people laugh and
giving making people around me have a
good time so I was never above doing
anything just super stupid just to get a
laugh you know and a lot of the times it
just came out weird or annoying you know
you got to try it out exactly like you
know you don't know what people are into
or not until you just go at it you go
for it you know uh and so it was always
kind of around there and um I had I've
had a lot of people like an
uncomfortable amount of people who like
just dead it in the face which is and
this is like this is the best way for
you to like Pat me in the back and then
slap me in the face at the same time
where they're like uh you should quit
rap and do
comedy right so it's like you're
hilarious like the disrespect and the
compliment like yeah like how how am I
supposed to feel about that you know uh
and so um it was always kind of around
there and people were always like dude
you should do comedy you should do
standup comedy because you know my
biggest platform for it uh for the
longest time was just Facebook you know
it would it would be on as a status or
like as a really dumb video I made or
something like that but um and at first
it was just kind of like oh let me give
people a good time and then I started
receiving a lot of messages from people
over the years that are like hey like
you know I don't want to sound weird or
anything like that but like I you're the
reason I get on Facebook at all ever and
it's like I have a really shitty day or
like I had a really shitty day today and
that thing you said dog I can't stop
laughing about it thank you you know so
people started just like thanking me for
doing that kind of stuff and like I I
kind of like I felt weird about it for
the longest time because I say really
like off-the-wall [__] and just things
that most people are like why would you
say that you know like uh and and so you
know I just I just kind of you know it's
kind of what's the the shock effect or
whatever right I can't remember what the
exact term of that is but like uh uh
that's just kind of that was just kind
of the person I am I always just kind of
said the thing that you know people are
thinking but don't want to say because
people don't say that kind of [__] we're
not allowed to especially not on
Facebook or social media and then people
started thanking me for doing those
things you know and and I like I felt
weird about I'm like people probably
hate me and think I'm like the biggest
dick you know and then people are just
like you're actually you make my days
better like I get on Facebook just to
see what you said that day because that
that's going to like make me smile you
know and then so I was like well all
right so I started doing more of that
and I think it was probably like uh I
know I had like a a New Year's
resolution either in like
2018 it started in 2018 and then I
revamped it in 2019 where I was like I'm
going to get on stage and do standup
comedy at least once you know I was like
I've been you know I've done this enough
and I've had enough people be like hey
you should do this you should try this
that I want to try you know um but I
didn't want it to you know I didn't want
to just go like oh let's go to an open
mic and get two minutes on the stage and
the opportunity presented itself to try
it when uh me and Ryan Reed uh you know
we kind of thought of this idea and and
he really he really kind of like ran
with it and he's been responsible for
our successes with these um but we kind
of had these ideas where where we got
tired of like performing at local shows
because it was just like you get five to
15 like just really lame performers and
then all your people have to show up and
wait and so like we wanted to throw our
own shows where it's like you can come
out uh we pick the performers and
there's not a ton of them and like you
can come out and enjoy coming out for
three hours you know like you you don't
have to pay $15 to come for like a
10-minute set like I I I hate doing that
to people just be come out on my show
come out on my show I'm only performing
for like 10 minutes you know and so you
have to pay well something that you guys
always do and I know because I've worked
with you and I've rehearsed with you
guys and I've practiced with you guys
before multiple shows is you guys
practice your performance everything
that you do is coin coinciding you guys
when you're when you're making a song
you're thinking big production you were
talking about how you wanted to be a
director and stuff when you're younger
acting whatever like you it's the way
that your your brain set works it's the
way that your brother's brain works it's
the way that Ryan Reed's brain works
like you
guys it comes across it's worth that $15
because all of you guys who are
performing are showing out it's not
there's a little bit of that flare from
hip-hop of like we're kind of competing
like let's let's you know bunkheads like
that's what hip-hop is but it's not too
much of that it's it's we're going to
come out in like we know where we're at
we know what's going on but we're going
to show you that we did practice and we
did put our heart into what what we did
so so you guys think big picture you you
practice what you're doing so so when
people come to your shows it's even if I
don't know this kind of music I don't
listen to it I don't know any of these
people I'm going to watch some people
perform their hearts out that's no doubt
and because you guys have put in the
time so we can put a pay in that but
yeah yeah I mean he he called me out on
it once before uh we were practicing for
a show that was coming out uh and you
know I was just cuz I we like you said
we really get into the performances you
because in that moment like that's
that's just kind of where we can really
shine and and and so in that Mo like
that's the only thing that matters is
this performance and just to give it to
the people you know um and so we we
really put our hearts into it and and I
remember we were practicing once and he
was just looking over there staring at
me and he's like dude what's wrong with
you I'm like what do you mean he's like
you're an entirely different person when
you perform I'm like what are you
talking about he's like you're such a
like loser in real life you're like so
lame it's like it hurts to see he's like
but then you start performing and you
turn into like a god like what where
does that come from you know who said
that you said you pointed oh I did I
just point I'm sorry I'm sorry I'm
pointing at my My Little My my little
brother he's like give me my cred I
called you a God he said he said don't
PL your eyes let him know who it is um
but yeah like you we we really do put
like everything we can into that and so
we were like having our own show that we
are responsible for and throwing like we
have more of an opportunity to do that
you know so we were able to find some
venues and and Paris Theater was had us
in for a few shows and I think they were
really awesome but um we had thrown one
in at the end of 2018 and that's the one
where me I don't know if you were I
think you were teing that one but that's
the one me and Ryan had a rap battle in
mhm yeah so like that was our like first
first halflife show that we put on ever
you know like the first like really big
one and so like one of the things that
we do other aside from just like you
know really rehearsing for the things
that like we want to add something into
each of these shows that's just a little
bit different than your like everyday
like local rap show or whatever
something that's fun something that's
exciting so at this one we did a rap
battle and we're like how about we see
the two guys that are doing all this go
at each other and we just just tore into
each other and you guys added this this
awesome like kind of like UFC banter
like on social media before you guys had
interviews like that whole thing dude
that to me that's someone I love that
dude I love that I think that more
people should should spend their time
not just on their like I'm only going to
you know remember my lyrics and and so I
can go out and just say them correctly
it's like no dude we you know let your
brain think as big as it really
does experience yeah we want them we
want people to like you know if you're
going to pay1 $15 we want you be there
and 2 3 hours later you'd be like who
damn is it has it already been that much
time like you we want want you to have a
good time like enjoy yourself you know
and so especially when it comes to like
social media and promotion and whatnot
we really try to put like the life and
the fun into it just to let people know
that that's how we are you know and
you've been to enough of our shows like
you know there's just a there's just a
different energy about it you know like
we we bring a lot of energy and the
people start giving back and we can just
feed off of it you guys brought that to
the jiren Benton show actually like
that bro that was tight like like you
guys had an energy in in in your crew
with you that was like on board too that
was no dude and when you get an
opportunity like that like you know you
got to be ready for it you got to you
just got to make the most of it you know
obviously like it's not like anything
super crazy came from it but a lot of
people from the town came out and you
know we had been doing this for so many
years already and like we've gone
through people don't like us and people
think we're whack and corny and this and
that like like we've gone through all of
that already you know and and now like
we're just kind of in a place where
people are realizing that we're we're
actually really serious about it and
like there's there's now there's just a
different level of respect that's
starting to come from people and that
feels really good because you know we
knew it was coming all along and that's
something that we've been fighting for
it's just now we're in a place where
we're capable of like making that happen
you know and so we started doing these
shows we did the first show had the rap
battle things went great and after that
point we decided that you know what like
we need to we need to make sure that
we're like doing something that's
positive with each of these shows as
well so we started and you know it
started then and now like we're doing it
continuously but like every Big Big Show
that we put on like all of the all of
the profits that we make from it go to
charity they go they go somewhere we we
usually pick out and research really
good or organization have you done three
different charities now or is it three
yeah can you name them real quick just
shout them out so uh the first one which
was uh the comedy show which I was
trying to lead into because we started
that one way way long ago but get back
uh yeah the first uh the first uh one
that we donated to was Dorne Becker
Children's Hospital uh that was back in
June of
2019 uh we we threw on a show it was
awesome that was the first that was the
first benefit concert that we ever put
on
war oh well if we take it back to
2013 uh you guys have been doing it I
mean it's building on yeah so me and me
and Ryan started doing our music
together in 2012 and then in
2013 uh we had we we we had put on a
show to help a buddy with like a project
project for school or something like
that and he wanted to put on a rap show
to raise money for uh for like War
veterans and things like that uh so our
first benefit show uh which yeah I guess
we technically put on as well um but
back like you know I don't really count
that one it was really super small I was
in a high school you know well dude we
we forget about all these things but
then if you have to look at your life on
a timeline it's like oh yeah I guess we
kind of were dipping our feed into that
we were kind of doing that like I I to
notice that's a especially a lot of the
things that I'm really good at now and
that I pred myself on are things that
back then I was just kind of like
dabbling a little bit here a little bit
there you know and then like after some
time you realize like damn like we can
actually do this you know you got let
yourself have it yeah and so then fast
forward six years to 2019 now we have
the ability to actually put on these
shows at a venue at a real venue and
make sure that people are having an
amazing time so uh the first one we put
on benefit show that we put on was in
June of uh of uh 2019 and that was for
Dorne Becker children's hospital and
that was you know we had done the rap
battle at the first show and at this one
like I actually pressed Ry and I was
like let me do comedy let me do stand up
let me do s and he and you know he was
like yes let's let's do it you know like
because that's something that he's kind
of been pull it down a little bit buddy
right about there yeah there you go just
so it doesn't cover your face so I can
like see your mouth when you're talking
it's those little things look at each
other you're right you're right yeah so
Ryan so Ryan was like hard pressed he
didn't want to let you do com no no no
no no no he just like that was just the
idea that I was bringing to him and he
was he was definitely on board from the
beginning um you know he says that he
always knew it was going to be good what
not but I feel like he might have had
his doubts then because it's it's
something very new and you know him
Giannis and everybody else are well
aware that I'm capable of just opening
my mouth and saying some [__] that
you're just like whoa right bro dude I
think he has genuine cares but I think
there's also a small pinge of him like
as each of us would have is almost like
that like I know I need to light a
little bit of a fire cuz like I want him
to do it too
like so I'm going to tell him that he
can't do it cuz I know he's he he he
never said no like I think like when I
first when I was first bringing it up
like you know he was like yeah yeah yeah
but it wasn't like he wasn't like super
excited it didn't feel like he was super
stoked on the idea you know because
again it's like at the time like he
knows you know he knows me better than
anybody else and he knows like I'm
liable to just say some [__] that he's
just G to like be like no God damn it
Max well in nowadays dude the world is
just weird and [__] with all the comedy
stuff so I mean with that one with that
first one we like I actually uh the
night before the show I performed my
whole standup set for him in his kitchen
okay just so he knew what he was what
were you wearing I I don't at the show
or in the kitchen in the kitchen I just
imagined I can't remember but I I
imagine it was something really basic
because we were just like going over you
know team things and and getting putting
in our last preparations for the show
all right you don't have to tell us
about the details of your guys'
relationship it's fine I won't press on
it anymore I don't remember what I was
wearing dude I wish I could tell you
what I was wearing but but I don't
remember uh so that was the first that
was the first show uh the second benefit
that we did was for YWCA Clark County uh
and that's an organization that helps uh
women and children that are dealing with
like domestic violence and uh things
like that so that was the second
donation we did and then the third one
happened uh December
6th uh in uh that we made a large
donation to boxes of Love uh and boxes
of love love uh I wasn't there
personally I had to go and work that
weekend but the team went on a really
big shopping spree and with all the
proceeds that we had made from the show
uh they had bought enough like clothes
gifts and things like that for foster
kids brought it to boxes of Love boxes
love said that was the largest single
donation that they'd ever received and
they have enough stuff from that one
donation for two years yeah that's so
epic yeah that's so tight that's so
worth it so proud so proud of the team
for that like like that you know and and
we just want to continue doing that kind
of stuff you know and it's just like
it's just being able to give it back to
the community and you know everybody has
their own things that you know they kind
of thrive in and that they're good at
you know for me it just happened to be
like comedy and stuff so we've done I've
done I've done the stand up there a few
times oh voice cracked there we go I
puberty sometimes too I know dude it's
weird it's I'm like 26 years old and I'm
like really still now really I I I am a
DJ who works in loud clubs who to talk
to to drunk people who say what 17 times
my voice cracks like at some point it's
just like my voice cracks in clubs more
often than it doesn't just like this is
who this is who I am now I'm training my
future metal voice I don't know I yeah
there we go I'm going for the Cohen CA
sound o oh Cen cambri sound I like that
that's what Jake Wilson would love that
where is he he was supposed to be here
he'll be here soon um so so switching
into Hedy
I had texted you I kind of wanted to
talk a little bit just we'll hang up on
just comedy in general um you're someone
who's never been you've never been
afraid to push the boundaries of Comedy
um and it's funny because comedians I
listen to a lot of like Joe Rogan and
stuff you know uh comedians they kind of
seem this is the worst word ever and I
hope you know what I mean like let's say
Dumber like more like uh uh gosh not
Dumber
uh simple to to other people so let's
see like the businessman like he's
thinking of a comedian like you're an
idiot you don't take life seriously
right yeah but realistically what I want
to express is I think comedians are are
one of the the more
important very important members of our
society because we have to see the irony
and the stupid [__] that we're doing
yeah absolutely we have to and comedians
are the ones who like like they say the
things that of course were like wait you
can't say that and then they reiterate
on how they [__] can say that and we
have to be able to have them say that in
order for things to work like this uh
and I think that's just super important
and and I I just I like expressing and
expanding on people's opinions of this
and of course I want your opinion on
this because I think
that the intelligence that comedians has
is is like maybe it's not compared to
like business intelligence whatever they
whatever that sentence might mean right
but it's it's a different kind of
intelligence like comedians are very
smart they understand things from a
level of like it's not that you're like
hey I need to point this thing about
Society so I can keep it a float like
you're doing it obviously to make people
laugh and and obviously for the
enjoyment of things so it's from a good
place in the first place but the the
complexity of the things even if it's a
simple joke comedy is is very important
with the way the culture and Society
work yeah um I
think I think the thing that I like I I
really appreci appreciate about comedy
and comedians is I don't think I don't
think necessarily you know that you know
like they're Dumber I understand the
perspective of like you know somebody
being like Oh you just don't take life
seriously or whatnot but I think of
course don't don't hang up on the word
absolutely not absolutely not I I think
the thing the thing that I can that I
really respect about like comedians is
is when you're looking at it from like
the you know the business perspective or
like the politically correct perspective
or whatnot there's there's like this
certain code of Ethics that the world
just has to follow to make sure that you
know this is what defines like a good
person or like a standup citizen or
something like that you know uh the
thing about comedy that's super
important I think is that um these like
kind of Ethics these codes these laws
these rules or certain things certain
standards certain patterns of behavior
or whatnot are just looked at as a norm
uh that that are so normal you know I
think the thing that I really respect
about comedians is like they they see
through the [__] like the majority
of the people do and they're not afraid
to just talk about the fact that this is
[__] right like I think that's that
that that's one of the key things that
makes them so crucial is like there's
people out there who can acknowledge
that this is [__] stupid right you
know like this is you are putting your
head down and charging through you're
the bulldozer that's like hey don't
forget about this stuff this is actually
happening right exactly and that's one
of those things where people would like
would come to me and just be like thank
you for like saying that you know I know
there going to be a lot of people who
like dis I'm not for everybody
absolutely not because I have a very
specific way of like thinking saying
things I have a very like kind of
Twisted sense of humor whatnot and I
don't really care you know whose opinion
is is about it so I'm going to say what
the [__] I want to say and what I need
to you have to you have to be
authentically you you do it took a
really long time and I brought this up
in the first time that we did a podcast
and and that one lost but yeah I'll
bring it up again but like I I remember
uh a post that you had made on on
Facebook what not where you were talking
about like you know there's there's
always going to be like 80% of the
people that see your stuff are kind of
going to be haters or they're going to
be disliking or they're going to have
something negative to say about it but
there's going to be this small portion
of people 20% of them uh that like love
what you're doing and that they're into
it you know and and basically like if
I'm remember corre the point of the post
was like if you spend a lot of time
weing about the 80% you know and trying
to please them even though they don't
like you already you're neglecting is
20% of people who do like you who do
[__] with you who think that the stuff
that you're saying is important it's
awesome it's it's cool the music
whatever the people who message you yeah
those are the 20% like when you spend
time thinking about like why doesn't
this person listen why doesn't this
person pay why do want to get reactions
from this person like why do these
people feel this type like like that it
can be kind of toxic because then you
start getting wrapped up in the fact
that people have negative opinions about
you as opposed to wrapping yourself in
the fact that there's people who have
positive opinions about you and you you
basically wrapped it up in saying that
the more you focus on this 20% that's
going to turn into this like the 80%
into the majority because people can see
people feel like the genuiness and the
authenticity when you're doing something
and you have like a purpose for doing it
you know and that you've really really
been about this this type of thing so
after some time people are going to
start to see that and that's true I had
so much anxiety about what people
thought about me and and how I was being
perceived and this and that you know and
I'd say like I would get anxiety just
from just like I'd be about to make a
post and suddenly like my heart's
beating I'm like dude like how are
people going with you bro those same
posts that I would post that you're
talking about I would do a lot of my
like motivational inspirational I'm
going to try to help people a little bit
with advice like what if it doesn't go
anywhere it's not going to get any likes
I I would reread I would post it and
then reread it immediately I'm like how
does it look as I'm scrolling through I
try to change perspectives but I do I do
also enjoy um I'm I uh I think it's
maybe a St of like a little bit of my
like obsessive compulsive Behavior but I
very I like uh the layout of something
like so once it's completed like in the
picture frame and then standing back of
my hands on my hips to look at it mowing
the yard and like just staring at it for
10 seconds when you're done those sort
of things so I think there is a lot of
that that they know about it's
aesthetically pleasing on social medias
but um but yeah a lot of times we we
have that like nervous like oh my god
did what I just say just break
everything like is everybody going to
hate me do they misunderstand me um
social media adds that kind of weird
layer so let's talk about social media
um it's it's cool
because I was always you know
career-wise in like kind of how people
know me what I would say was always like
DJing right like that's kind of like how
I was known but I was also kind of since
2010 or 11 since I I got Facebook I've
always posted these long like hey like I
was kind of had this thought and I think
that like you guys should take better
care of yourselves and here's how I've
taken care of myself I don't know like
whatever like some sort of inspirational
motivational like I never wanted to be
like a life coach or a therapist or like
a conversationalist or whatever the heck
is happening
like but looking back it's like oh I
have been posting those things I have
been inspiring people the same thing
that you got people would message you
and say like dude you made me laugh
today thank you so much people would
message me like all these years and say
like dude that hit me hard thanks I need
to hear that those sort of things
I I'm just I like where you're going I
think that you're an awesome rapper and
I think that everything you're doing
event planning too and I don't think you
should ever stop any of those things but
I just I I just want to let you know
that I don't know you super well but I'm
super on board with you being a comedian
I think that it follows like I know that
we kind of paint Facebook and Twitter
into these like dorky kind of like funny
meme worlds but as a pagan history Pagan
history that sounded weird a peg like
boom pointing uh hammering a peg into
history I still can't say right pegging
history yeah but at this point in
history so let's say we're looking at
history on a timeline like uh you know
just because it's the dorky little f
with the blue and then it's the cute
little bird on Twitter doesn't mean
these things aren't huge you know a lot
of our development as as young men was
from Facebook and that's how we learned
about our society we learned about our C
unfortunate truth it's crazy right and
it's something that work this is just
like a Pastime and it's just a silly
like thing we do everybody just does and
but um you know there was a part of you
that was taking some of that serious and
there was a part of me that was taking
some of that serious on my side you know
it's not that I was only funny or or not
that you were only funny on social media
and I was only advice giving on social
media like we had different areas of our
life we're always these ways but it's
kind of interesting to look like if you
we joke about and don't take these
Twitter and Facebook seriously in some
senses but it's a lot of our a lot of
who we are and our upbringing and a lot
of like I think that you know maybe if
people didn't message you and say or or
give you a like or say like hey I do
appreciate this like maybe you wouldn't
have like tried so hard and kept like
full force going oh I I absolutely need
like some kind of
like what's what's the word I'm looking
for like like affirmation from people
that like I do I do otherwise I feel
like I'm a piece of [__] right like like
I can make something like this is so
cool this is so cool put it out you know
and maybe Facebook algorithm is on some
dumb [__] that day and it doesn't really
go anywhere and I'm like [__] it sucks
it's horrible nobody likes it you start
listening to it in ways that you're like
this does suck huh you convince yourself
ways that it if people don't kind of
give me that [__] validation that's
the word I was looking for if I don't
get the yeah if I if I don't get
validation from people that I feel like
I'm failing you know uh and that's
something that I've kind of had to like
train myself to stop doing so much
because I was putting a lot of uh weight
on to what people's opinions were like
it never came across that way I've
always appeared as a person who does not
not give a [__] what you think but I
said this thing that only people who
don't give a [__] what you think would
say but I'm back here like [__] [__]
[__] why I say that why did I say you
know and then now I just go now I got I
got to double down on it I got to stick
with it because I said it you know and
after some time you know the the kind
the nerves about it went away and now
like for me you know once I started
paying attention to that 20% I'm you
know I'm more comfortable with myself
than I ever I've ever been because like
I don't give a [__] if you don't like me
like
I I love what I'm doing you know right
now like I'm inspires the [__] out of me
man thank you dude I appreciate that
means so much that means so much to hear
because like we've been working at it so
hard for so long and like this is the
first time I'd say really like
2019 on like this is when I'm like
really really feel like you know I'm
starting to come into the artist that
I've always wanted to be like I'm
starting to sound the way I wanted to
sound as a raer as a as a hip hop artist
I'm saying the things that I felt like I
should be saying you know I'm making the
kind of jokes as a comedian that I
should have that that I've always wanted
to be making you know I'm getting
reactions from people that I've always
wanted to be getting like I'm finally
coming into it you know and and people
are seeing it and people are starting to
acknowledge the fact like oh damn like
and for a lot of people it comes across
as like you know like you know tell tell
me if you think like a lot of people
might look at you and assume that you're
just a lot more successful than you
really are because you know the way you
portrayed on like social media or or or
just just the way kind of people around
perceive small town Fame thing exactly
that's people are like just like oh dude
like you know I I just put out uh we
just had a song come out me and my buddy
his name is Don coil uh we have an EP
coming out but we just put out our first
single and we've been working on an EP
for the last year we just put out our
very very first song Together name it
what's the name it's called no
explanation by coil and pain uh it's on
Spotify it's everywhere uh it's it's an
incredible song uh it's it's it's for
ladies uh you know it's it's enjoyable
it's like it's a very like Club Banger
type song but it's like it Praises
Independent Women uh and just
Independence in in females and women
what when does the rest of the video
came out cuz I know there was a teaser
yeah so we we put out a teaser with it
uh and and that was just you know uh the
the rest of the video is going to come
out in February we are filming the rest
of it next next week uh as of right now
we just have like performance takes or
whatnot and we decided to drop a little
like teaser of that with the performance
takes just to kind of get people more
intrigued into actually listening to the
song you know uh because it's a really
dope dope dope song like I you know
again I'm finally at a place where I'm
more confident in the stuff that I'm
putting out than I've ever been before
uh and it just it sounds so phenomenal
uh the rest of the project is going to
be crazy too but that just came out and
uh I'm I'm responsible for the videos
for that too uh so we have a friend of
ours I've been filming videos for the
entire team like for the team not the
entire team yet but we have plans for
all of 2020 um but I'm doing videos for
them I'm responsible for doing the
videos for everybody in the team uh on
top of my own videos uh so I got a buddy
of mine His Name Is eor Mud uh and he is
starting to hold the camera for me you
know I'm finally giving it to someone
and trusting them with it and is he is
he a videographer are you kind of like
teaching him or like he's uh I'm not I'm
not even he's he's he's into it without
me like independent of me like he he
loves it and like he just he's he's
upgrading his equipment he like you know
we just got an actual stabilizer because
he wanted a stabilizer uh and he's he's
looking at buying all these things like
this camera right here that we have this
is Ryan's camera and I am you know I'm
just so grateful that he allows me to
use it and to play with it and to do
things with it because he knows that's
my passion I'm just really and I'm
getting really good at it you know video
wise y That's the you guys have the
coolest friend I mean again I keep
mentioning all of you like the boys like
you guys are just like I'm going to work
on this thing and then come back and
show my friend well he works on this
thing and he's going to come back and
show me I feel like you guys collab on
so much stuff together and it's gotten
so much better we we we doubled up on
the team this last year it used to be
just me Ryan and yanis and now we've
included uh Ryan's Ryan's love
Karissa uh We've included uh roulette
Elgato who is an incredible artist and
he's been killing it and murdering he
did he did m center this year that
that's crazy oh that's right he was who
and he had Ryan on stage with him oh
right right dude yeah m center that's
that like you know and so he's a part of
the team now and then we have Jess wild
and I just did a music video for him I
did a music video for roulette Delgato
as well but those two are out already uh
just wild it's a song called star kid
roulette it's a remix to a song called
dear Rose uh but I just did videos for
both of them uh and they just they
turned out so so so was so dope uh so
yeah we just you know we I try to stay
busy you I forgot what the original
question even was but talk about this
your song that just came out let's
expand on the song itself h no
explanation okay so no
explanation uh it's it's between me and
and and J decoy III I didn't give his
full name the first time but he is an
incredible incredible artist and
somebody that I've looked up to for a
very long time and he approached me
a year and a half ago and was like hey
we should make some songs together uh
and I freaked out like I was fan girl I
was like what what this is crazy you
know uh because he's he's he's so dope
he's such a talented artist uh and so we
started working on music together but uh
no
explanation that one that one we just
felt like it's a really quick song it's
just two minutes long uh I do the hook
he does the verse I do the hook again
and the song is over uh but like I said
it's uh it kind of just Praises uh
Independence and women and and the
independent woman and and it just kind
of like uh from my hook it kind of comes
from the perspective of me talking to
somebody and basically letting them know
like dog you should probably just you
know pump the brakes you don't have a
chance here bro like like she's not that
type of girl like like you don't got a
chance there like you know this is the
type of woman that she is you know and
he uh J wrote his verse you know off the
same thing because I like I had sent him
the pro the the song with the hook
already and whatnot and was like this is
kind of what I'm thinking uh I want you
to do the verse you know and and you
know we got to talk you know she's she's
she's independent she doesn't give a
[__] like she's just she's just a bad
[__] like whatever without saying bad
[__] uh because we don't disrespect uh
but it's it's a very like it's a very
Club Banger uh but it's like a it's kind
of like a positive one you know like
this is this is one that I I wouldn't
even have a problem it's got a few swear
words but I would let my daughter listen
to it and be like girl this is this is
the vibe you need to be on like
independent you don't have time for [__]
boys you don't have time for any of the
[__] like Get It Go Get It Like It's
you just do it so that's kind of what
the song is about you know I feel it I
feel it it's fun it's a really fun song
I love it uh how do you when you first
initially so the first Concepts like
obviously it starts with idea when you
first get the idea what what's your
situation like I had my homie Kendall
John's on here um he's a he's singer of
a a metal band met I know kendle Johns
yes but uh so he um he was talking about
his writing process he's like dude like
I go it's like I get two VOD cotas at
the bar and I just get [__] up and
then the lyers start coming you know
like he he he gives out his process
what's your what's your process for
comedy and for for lyric writing or even
just I mean because you write out
elaborate ideas no doubt I'm sure but
what do you just try to catch it on the
Fly and throw it into the notes or or
what's your process yeah uh that's funny
that you know he uh he gets inspired off
of like alcohol that's fny because for
me once I start sipping on any alcohol
the like creative process just kind of
goes out the window for me I and I don't
want I don't want to focus on it anymore
it's uh for me like uh weed kind of
Sparks the creative process more than
anything like that's so so before I
start writing before I start editing
before I start doing anything like that
I usually like to take a hit or two a
weed you know like that that and that
kind of gets me kind of zoned in on it
you know um as far as writing process
for music uh I I like I try to look for
inspiration everywhere for for a long
time a lot of my music like the lyrics
were just kind of like I'm dope you're
not dope ah you know like that's I mean
you guys are good at enunciation and
word flow and pronunciation and I I
spent a lot of time just trying to
improve myself and so a lot of the the
lyrics come out just just braggadocious
because I'm just trying to see how how
much I could rhyme what kind of schemes
I can play with what kind of metaphors I
can drop things like that so it's just
kind of training the tongue type of a
situation for a long time uh but you
know now I try to I try to find more
inspiration everywhere else and I do
write based on my life a lot I haven't
put out a lot of like super personal
music but that's because like I'll write
the personal stuff and that's enough
therapy for me like I'll write like it
it helps me like writing about you know
what I'm going through or whatever as
music it helps me process it a lot
better because as I'm writing it I kind
of like I kind of like put myself
through through a level of therapy and
like trying to explore why I feel the
way I feel you know what I'm saying like
I have this song it never came out uh
but there's a verse on it where I
started writing it and I started writing
it about my dad right and and about all
the anger I had towards my father and it
was about halfway through the verse as
I'm writing this and trying to just
express how I feel you you know what he
did to our family and how how much he
[__] it up that like you know this is
how I feel about you as a person this
like you know and I'm just kind of
listing off these qualities on who who I
really know he is and not who people
think he is because you know I get the I
get the whole like put on a show thing
from my dad my dad is an awesome person
I'm not I'm not trying to speak ill on
him or anything like that we had a bumpy
past but like he's always been the
person that people just like gravitate
to in love like he's just got that
Persona the Charisma you know like
people people people just love who he is
like he's a really fun person really
easy to get along with things like that
but uh I just I made this song and I
just started calling out all these like
terrible qualities and was like people
see this but I see this you know this
and that so I was like tearing it and it
was halfway through this verse I looked
back at what I wrote and I was like I'm
talking about
myself I was I was I was I was in my 20s
you know and I was trying to vent all
this anger and frustration for the type
of person that I thought my dad was and
I like realized I was writing a verse
about myself you know what I'm saying
like like and it was you know and that's
just that's the way that it was written
and like I was just like holy [__] like
wow like like that the writing process
like that does that for me sometimes you
know because I just start to kind of
explore things that I wouldn't have like
had the time or the desire to even think
about but now I'm trying to think about
how to like make all this rhyme and get
all this right amount of emotion now and
I have the song recorded I just never
put it out because I never had a never
two unreleased tracks we need some from
the old days we need your first track
out too I there's I probably have like
somewhere in the ballpark of like 20 to
30 recorded songs that uh are just never
came out oh no doubt probably more than
that for sure but I mean in a million
starts yeah you know but this this was a
powerful song this was one that I really
wanted to put out and I probably will
someday because like the the way that it
ties up is actually super super powerful
um there's no rush man so I you know I
write this whole verse and it's like you
you know you never hear me like address
my father you just assume that based on
what I'm talking about he's probably
talking about his dad or like a parental
figure that walked out on him or whatnot
like that's just kind of what it sound
so I never directly address address it
and so the whole time like I have you
the you know the listener believing that
they're listening to me like chastising
my father but because I realized what I
realized halfway through it you know I
continued the verse as I needed to
the very very like very last lines where
it was it was still kind of I was kind
of addressing him it was like I know
exactly who you are um like I know
exactly what you're about because I'm
talking about myself so like the the
song and the song ends with me saying
because I'm talking about myself and so
as if you listen to the verse door man
if if you listen to the verse the first
time you're like he's talking about his
dad when you go and listen to it the
second time through and and put the fact
that I'm talking about myself it like
unlocks and opens so many more then it's
like oh [__] damn [__] you know so like
I definitely I like I try to for my
writing process I try to pull as much
inspiration I can from what's actually
going around me but I don't like writing
in like a direct way of like this is
exactly kind of what I'm going through
you know I write about what what it
makes me feel like you know so when I'm
trying to write like a deeper emotional
song I'm not writing about what's
happening I'm writing about how I feel
about what's happening right so then
that way when someone's listening to it
um they're not listening to my story
they're listening to their own because
they're they're just relating feelings
right so they're they're relating how
how just something like sentiments and
things like that you know so it's not
I'm not describing my situation you know
bold face I'm describing it on like an
emotional or like on a spiritual level
almost you know and so when somebody
listens to it it's not just like damn
this kid's been through some [__] it's
just like [__] me too yeah you know
so like that that's that's how I try to
to to to write it and I mean aside from
that the rest of the stuff that I try to
do I try to I really like high energy
material and things like that so I like
a lot of my music is stuff you could
work out to you could you could like go
on runs to you could go and beat
somebody's ass to I don't I don't know
it's like high energy you know that's
just the fun for me you know I feel like
I need to throw some of you guys' [__]
on me I have this playlist called you
want to fight [__] and it's got a lot
of like puya suicide boys and stuff
there's I got some songs to recommend
for that playlist right I'm going to
have you you got to hit me with like
your top three I'm throw on the playist
absolutely unfor here's the thing though
like I've I've grown so much especially
in the last like two years as an as an
artist and overall
that the stuff that I have out online
now aside from you know not including
what just came out I don't even like it
anymore you know because I feel like
I've come so so much farther you know is
such a weird gift and curse some of
likewe situation at the time you're like
this is the dopest [__] I've ever done
ever everever represents me in every way
and then next year it's just like please
stop talking about that you know you
think about famous people who have like
a top 40 song that gets popular and they
just have to tour the world and just say
the same thing and they're like think
about like in sync and stuff they're
like 30 years later they're like we have
to are they still touring or I don't
know back street or isn't one of them
touring are they probably back street T
wow yeah crazy dude yeah they're back
all right or like uh Smashmouth they got
one song that they were allowed to do
ever what what song what smash mail have
uh the the one on track hey now you're a
rockar I feel like I have other songs I
feel like I when I feel like but you
don't what do you DJ I know I can't I
feel like when I play at bars where I'm
like let's make these [__] sing
cuz they're pretty drunk It's I can find
some Smashmouth there maybe it is just
Allstar I could be just I I I just I I I
know I've never listened to any
Smashmouth aside from
Allstar that's a damn good song though
you can't deny in wonderful it goes dude
it's yeah I goes hard shout out to smash
Bou you all stars uh give give me a
little low down on your comedy side of
writing is Is this different or like
have you had like is you know have you
had to be like oh I have to be a more
funny person or a less serious person
like uh you know to be in the mindset of
like uh uh someone who's writing rap
songs that can be listened to in the gym
you're not going to be like always in a
super joking mood all the time you know
so these are like different areas of
your psyche of your emotional person
that you lock into like for yeah like
sometimes for a couple hours while you
write songs but sometimes it's like I
got to live this way for a few weeks so
I can lock into the character of sorts
um when it come time to like start for
you to start like writing comedy to we
like okay I'm going to perform this on
stage let's let's talk about that area
like when you started approaching the
comedy and started writing your comedy
to actually perform so um we we we'll go
into that first performance cuz that was
definitely the best one that I've had uh
and I did what like half an hour on
stage I planned for like 18 minutes or
something like that and I was on there
for 33 when it's your own show I guess
go at it I think you were at the end
anyway right or something close to it it
was towards the end yeah was it was
right before our the last music set
which was our own and then I got way too
drunk and ruined that sorry R love you
bro uh I got way too way too drunk
during the comedy set but
um the way I prepared for that one um I
wanted to
like the the thing that's different
about the way I did my first comedy show
and the way that other people might have
done their comedy shows is is you know
most of the people that are starting out
to doing comedy they're going to like
you know a comedy club or an open mic
night or or something like that where
they're just kind of in that world and
you know you might get like a few
minutes on stage here or or something
like that and so you just kind of got a
kill with that um but when we had the
the opportunity presented to you know
have our own show and I was like Ryan
let me do comedy like I knew that I'm
going to get no less than 15 minutes you
know so I could be on there and just
kind of shine as long as I wanted to you
know uh and it ended up being half an
hour so I was trying to plan for just 15
to 20 minutes I ended up being a half an
hour cuz you know like you start getting
inspired up there and saying other
things and whatnot uh it was great but
the way I tried to plan for that I knew
who the audience was going to be MH I
knew it was going to be people who
already [__] with us I knew it was going
to be people who already follow me on
Facebook so they already know that like
if I'm saying something it's going to be
funny what not so I already was going to
be going on stage with the thought in
mind that the people out there already
know me they already know I'm funny so
they're expecting to laugh and because
of that they're going to laugh more
already right so I I kind of had that
benefit you know that's a great
confidence to be able to lock into I
mean I know that being like a popular DJ
in the area like if I know that I'm
going to have like 20 homies in the
crowd I'm probably going to be a little
more cocky in my dance mean exactly you
already know these people have [__]
with you already so this is going to go
well it's just like having your boys
with you at all times you just exactly
exactly exactly and and then I and I did
have all my boys with me so it was
perfect uh and uh so so I I kind I
already knew who the audience was going
to be and I had enough time you know
doing my Facebook comedian [__] to kind
of know what people are reacting to and
what they're not reacting to so I've
already had you know how some people
might say I've had my ear to the streets
right so I've been picking up on what's
what's what's cool what's not uh what
people are talking about what's not so I
I really like orchestrated that whole
set to be geared at Millennials uh and
to be geared at just certain you know
certain things that you know are are
common among Millennials that are funny
are you so like I had jokes
about uh [__] single
moms uh that was a great one I jokes
about single moms I had jokes about like
uh guys and just kind of like over
described what your typical white guy is
supposed to be like and just kind of was
like this is not me and then I had like
12 minutes on
dickpics yeah the dickpic thing was
hilarious cuz you had a slideshow no I
did not have a slideshow for the dickpic
thing uh just kidding that that I don't
know I don't know how I get away with
that it's just that here's dickpics and
they're just actual dickpics on a
slid guys what's up with this time like
so all these guys are in the
crowd um so like a lot of what I wrote I
was already kind of thinking I was like
this is these are things that like you
know Millennials might be talking about
might be laughing about already or
whatnot um and then it was just my own
personal spin on things because I know
like like I said I'm not I'm not for
everybody uh but there is just a certain
spin on my comedy that's unique to me uh
you know it's to the point where like
people will send me certain things
certain memes certain jokes and be like
this made me think of you this and that
makes me feel so good when people do
that just like a like I'm like leaving
an impression yeah uh so yeah the the
way the way I wrote that whole thing I
and I actually like I put myself through
like boot camp for that that because uh
I wrote it all out you know I was like
okay this might be funny this might be
funny this might be funny and then I
kind of went in and started expanding on
each of these things uh and then what I
did was I actually recorded like got an
audio recording of me just saying it out
loud you know and just reading out what
what I'm supposed to say and I just
started listening back to it over like
because I had like three months to
prepare or something like that so I was
like prepared like months in advance you
know you wait till the last second yeah
I was I was just listening I'd be
listening to it listening to it and then
I was like okay this segments not that
[__] funny I need to get rid of this
you know and I need to hear and I need
to like have it go through a few
different times to kind of catch a
different perspective on it and be like
this isn't as funny as I thought it was
going to be you know what saying how has
that been has that been like a lot of
[__] like like like discouraging is that
like God dang I really thought that was
hilarious but honestly that sucked or
whatever and it's it's the same thing as
just kind of like what you know I might
have like said or posted something that
I thought was really funny on on
Facebook and then I didn't realize how
people would take it and then people
start coming at me and the comments
about what I just said or whatnot and
then I'm like oh [__] you know maybe
maybe I maybe I shouldn't have done that
worded differently yeah maybe I could
have worded that differently maybe you
know but at that point I'm just like I'm
that person who doesn't give a [__] so
I'm like I'm like I double down on what
I go with anyway you know so I'm trying
to avoid kind of falling into that kind
of yeah no dude you're going to avoid it
like a [__] Champ there's no doubt
about it you handle it well you dude you
you're you know a lot of what you do on
Facebook and and what you do is a
personality and that's like okay so
you're kind of like you got to consider
a comedian a lot of times or even just
someone in your position in this in
society is like kind of like the jester
who's like you know not that they're
like back then they probably weren't
allowed to make fun of the king and
queen to the king and queen's face but
now what we have is like the gesture can
kind of make fun of anything the gesture
of our society so it's it's important
but it's funny when you like have to we
have this world of like deep platforming
and like like I'm going to find
something you said so long ago and like
did you did you watch that Kevin Hart
documentary on I haven't seen it yet but
I do want to like I do want I love Kevin
Hart dude I think he's do I think he's
great A lot of people are like oh he's
overrated and this no I think he's great
D I think he deserves all the success
always the weirdest sentence when people
say that [__] no you should watch it but
he he talks about like like one thing he
said long ago and then people pulled it
up and they're like you think this and
he's like dude I'm I don't think that
anymore like that was a joke back then
that in society it was it wasn't weird
to say and that was like something that
that that that happened for me I um I
had ended up making a new Facebook page
like two or three years ago uh because
my original one I'd had from when I was
14 or 15 years old and then when
Facebook started doing memories uh and
just bringing back everything you posted
on that day from however many years ago
or whatever I just right I started
seeing so much just [__] up things
that I had said that I thought you I'm
15 16 years old you know I to I had my
space I had a you know and like it kept
popping up you know and I'd just be
deleting and deleting and deleting and
then it would be like popping up like oh
someone tagged you in this post and now
I'm in this post and I'm like reading
myself in the comments and I'm just like
dude what the [__] like like I I like I
said some like I'd be saying some really
off-the-wall [__] up [__] and I
remember as a 15 16 yearold my thing was
like oh I want to push the boundary like
I I want to piss people off like I want
to do that you know like I didn't learn
how to do that taste give any kid that
power give give a punk rock kid a cell
phone they don't exist tell the world I
said things that it's like you know if
it was to come back years later it would
definitely bite me in the ass and could
potentially be like career Destroyer
because I said some like foul [__] in my
day like for me it's like I'm like
whatever who cares and then once it
starts popping up in the memories I'm
just like so after deleting enough of
those posts I was like I'm deleting this
entire Facebook it's just
starting it sucks you have to be scared
of it I guess I do get it but it's it's
something that I want to make apparent
dude it's people's careers get destroyed
all that like
Kevin Hart was going to be on you know
uh hosting the Grammys or the Oscars or
something like that and then you know he
had a joke about you know what if his
son came and told him that he was gay or
something like that and it kind of had
to deal with that and you know he could
it was one of those things where it's
like yeah sure he could have phrased it
differently but he didn't say anything
that was just like and back then I
remember laughing at the damn joke like
it was hilarious it didn't stand out to
me it was something that you're like oh
this is [__] up like it's like this is
Fu well the way that [__] is going the
last few years with like all the whole
like people find one thing that that you
said way back you tweeted way back then
and and they found it I mean it's yeah
probably started from like the
presidency stuff right we found like
okay our president like can't be saying
things like this or yeah you know grab
her by the [__] like Jesus like that's
insane our president but but but so that
sentence right there like not the
sentence itself but just the fact that a
president a higher person whatever
presidential candidate at that time uh
got away with saying those things
there's a lot of people it sprouted
sparked a lot of people in the world who
were like wait we can't say those things
and then so people get on a wild goose
hunt and they start looking for
everything everybody said that was bad
everything everybody that was bad it's a
weird thing we we can't like evolve and
and get better and and dude like i' be
willing to bet a lot of us when we were
the ages of first getting social media
12 and 13 and 14 and 15 whatever said a
lot of dumb stuff I used to quote like
every song that I listen to I listen to
a lot of kid cuy and I would post the
whole lyrics online and like act like it
was me so you can guess what I've said
on soci and it's still there and if
somebody wants to point up like you said
this at one point in my life I'm like
yeah I sure did 100% if you look at the
date that's when it said like oh so you
were 16 I'm like yeah yeah I was 16 can
we can we like let I refuse to allow
people to like like try to you know like
deplatform people and like you did this
this is do we have to have room for
change because people people do change
man like people genu like I my mind
state has changed so much from when I
was a kid like I grew up I grew up in
the church and I had a very specific way
of like looking at things at the time
and like now it's entirely different you
know for the longest time you know
homosexuality was just the worst sin in
the world for me you know because they
told me it was yeah you know and it's
like after after enough time I'm like
why yeah like why there's there's so
many things that you guys are doing that
are like even more [__] up than two
men loving each other like why are they
on trial for that sh you know like and
so like like my my mindset has changed a
lot like I've come I I've come a very
very long way a lot of people if you
were to ask people who knew me in high
school they would tell you I was like
the biggest sexist chauvinist stick like
pig ever I thought it was a part of my
humor back then you know but also I grew
up in a Russian culture where the wife
does what the husband says she stays at
home she cooks this and that this like
and they love the women are fine with
that like that that's cool when you're
looking at like American culture they're
like how dare you oh my God oh my God oh
my God when you're looking at Russian
culture they're like yeah this is this
is just life this is all it is you know
people have a problem
understanding like like the basis
sentences like they don't understand
that people are different but like they
really like really just stop and think
about that like whatever you do in your
life like you go Monday through Friday
to your job and you come home to your
cottage and whatever Louisiana but
there's literally people who live a
completely different life it's not like
they just have a different house in a
different whatever like everything they
do the way that they speak the things
that they mean when they speak like
culture is so Broad and I think
sometimes we try to smash it together
and it's like it doesn't go like that
it's it's you got to be gentle this is
going to take many years for us to
figure out and in the meantime we can't
have people [__] running into the
streets with TIY torches like you said
this 28 years ago you suck like Jesus
man it's just Madness so I I to D more
power to you keep saying what you're
saying keep talking about the
intelligent things you're talking about
because I think it's seriously again
comedians are intelligent and they're
very important in society and that was
when I initially messaged you like that
was like a um I probably was just like
super baked or something and saw when
your Facebook post and I was like oh my
God we got to talk about comedy in
society so oh yeah um H yeah but I do
want to make sure um we talk about
anything in your Artistry world I want
to make sure um we're getting a little
up here in time I want to keep chatting
for a little bit here but uh make sure
we've covered everything like we have
your new newest song released do you
have anything coming up any shows coming
up um what what what's coming up next
for you guys in the coming let me
hopefully be able to remember everything
because there's there so much going on
right now which is awesome this is this
is this is what I want
give us locations and stuff too for
people who don't know all the all the
places you're talking about things
exactly yeah absolutely so
uh next weekend I'm shooting the rest
the remainder of the no explanation
music video uh that's the song that just
came out coil and pain check us out on
Spotify uh I'm filming the rest of the
music video next Saturday and I'm hoping
to have that music video out within the
first half of February I don't have a
release date on it just yet depends on
how next Saturday goes um but yeah we
have a we have an actress that's going
to be in the video uh and I think she's
just going to elevate the quality of
that project tfold you know uh so that's
happening uh within the next month uh
currently working on uh a recap video
for halflife entertainment just to kind
of show people what our year was like in
2019 uh what we were able to accomplish
the benefit shows that we were doing you
know uh our community outreach and
whatnot uh I'm working on a documentary
for roulette Delgado uh kind of
detailing his journey to the Moda Center
uh and kind of getting him prepared he's
got an album called uh coming out in
March was it right yianis coming out in
March I think it was coming out in March
I think it was coming out in March it's
called a superhuman volume two right
superum I got right when when's National
Women's Day March 8th March 8th okay
perfect March 8th uh roulette Delgado
superhuman Volume 2 I hope I'm getting
that right I think I am uh and I'm
featured on that project Giannis is
featured on that project Ryan's featured
on that the whole team is featured on
that project it's an amazing project
that's coming out uh so I'm working on a
documentary for that uh we are about to
get started on an entire video series
for kitis Yannis my little brother right
back there he put out an EP about a year
or so ago uh and we're building a whole
film series out of the songs off of that
EP uh so that's going to be incredible
it's going to be an awesome thing to try
out uh on top of that uh my own EP uh
the coil and pain EP is uh supposed to
come out probably in April uh you spell
coil coil c y l e want someone to go to
Spotify I'm be like what coil like you
know recoil no no coil c o y l e the and
symbol p a y n e coil and pain uh we
kind of sound like a you know divorce
lawyers that's what it sounds like cool
it's catchy catchy divor exactly uh but
no we have an EP coming out uh we're
hoping to have that out in March or
April we have several different music
videos that we're planning for that that
are going to be amazing again uh um I'm
just taking over the whole videography
aspect for the team and uh I intend for
those to just keep getting better and
better because that's something that we
really Thrive with uh and so uh we're
doing all that next February I don't
know if I'm allowed to talk about about
this yet uh so if I'm I can take this
part out just let me know if okay I
don't I think it'll be fine uh I just
don't have all the details on it yet but
uh Andrew kiggins is putting on a show
at the Regent uh in Long View on
February 15th it's going to be a comedy
show uh and I've been asked to perform
on that one so I am going to be showing
up and doing a set uh uh over at the
Regent in Long View February 15th so
excellent and then on February 22nd
halflife entertainment is putting on
another show and we're going to be at
The Cruise Room Annex in Portland
Oregon uh Cruise Room CR U room uh and
that's happening on the uh 22nd of
February we have a show coming up that's
going to be music I'm not doing comedy
at that one but I will be performing my
music love you're still doing all this
stuff like you're not just you're still
doing all of it so great it's there's so
much there's let's add one more thing
yeah right you you have like a life
outside of it you have job you work
you're a father like yeah I like
incredible man I'm forgetting something
I know I'm forgetting something right
now but that there's something else
that's coming out that I am absolutely
like is slipping so after February
15th February 15th is comedy and then
February 15th is comedy at the Regent in
Long View Washington uh February 22nd is
music at The Cruise Room Annex in
Portland Oregon uh with halflife
entertainment the entire team and they
are an incredible and talented group of
people uh so you guys should absolutely
come out if you're able to to any of
those shows who is officially in
halflife who uh so Ryan Reed you do a
little you want to do a little bio on
him just as a homie on Ryan yeah on each
everybody on everybody yeah okay yeah
absolutely man let me let me introduce
you guys to my team really quickly okay
so Ryan Reed uh me and him go way back
to first grade when he first moved up to
Kelo Washington me and him have been
friends since then we both started
highcap which is a program that you go
to once a week when you're in Elementary
School uh and so we became closer
friends because of that program um smart
because I guess I wasn't trying to go
but it's for you know high high cap it
stands for highly capable and gifted um
I'm not trying to flaunt that right now
because I don't think I'm that smart uh
but that that kind of that's kind of
where we built a relationship and back
then me and him like we kind of wanted
to do music together anyway and this is
like third grade fourth grade fifth
grade you know what I'm saying uh but we
didn't know what we were going to do so
I had moved off to Vancouver when I was
12 and me and him started doing hip-hop
music uh individually on our own terms
and then we came back together when we
were about 18 years old and over the
time we had like had each other on
MySpace and you know we're just kind of
going back and forth about the music and
helping each other critiquing each other
songs things like that uh and so we kind
of built this kind of relationship on
like oh we're homies we both rap let's
kind of help each other out with that um
uh Ryan is the the the founder of
halflife life entertainment uh back then
it was half Clan entertainment uh but he
he's the one that kind of started that
whole brainchild and then uh at 18 years
old he asked me to come on and uh be a
hype man for him at a show it worked out
really well we made a whole entire
mixtape with each other that summer the
summer of 2012 it was legendary it was
epic it was called get hyy I know
there's people out there who remember
that and probably still have that CD
with them uh it was awesome but that was
the first project that we put out
together um and ever since then we've
just been taking Half-Life entertainment
a lot seriously we changed it from half
Clan to halflife you know for obvious
reasons when you start talking about him
um but uh yeah Ryan Reed is is the the
founder and and really the the big dog
of halflife entertainment he produces
and raps he's a he's a producer he's a
phenomenal producer he makes his own
music he's a great rapper uh and he is
the one who has been putting on who's
been like pulling the strings behind the
scenes for all of these shows that we're
doing in the benefit shows and what so
uh he's he really he's really kind of
champion taking the uh uh business side
of things and trying to make sure that
you know we're looking good as a company
uh as a business and uh so he's he's
kind of responsible for those kind of
the really big decisions and things like
that and uh we've been building that
together for a really really long time
uh and we kind of specialize in our own
separate areas uh but he was the one who
was responsible for getting uh my
brother Giannis on board because Yannis
was like I want to be a partner I was
like n dude you ain't you ain't about
none and so then he went to Ryan and he
was like hey Ryan I want to be Ryan was
like yeah of course so I was like it was
a couple of months I backstab my
brother I was like all right that's cool
he hangs up the phone I'm gonna call
Ryan right now uh and then in uh in
August of uh oh well I mean yeah we
we'll get to that part so then that's
Ryan then we have Giannis kidis that's
my brother you guys have met him he is
an R&B musician uh he is incredible he
has an EP out it's called past Chasers
that's on Spotify kitis that's k a n
D- I uh very simple it's kind of spelled
the way it sounds it's better to spell
it sometimes it does brain fart yeah it
does it's weird it's weird it's weird
but yeah he uh he he makes Incredible
music we're about to get started on um
uh the whole film series for his EP uh
it's already out he's got new music
that's uh that's coming up the pipeline
uh that's really awesome and you know
you're probably going to get him on the
show and he can go more into depth about
that so it was me Ryan and Yannis for a
very long time and then in summer of
last year uh Ryan came to me and he was
like hey man I'm thinking about like
adding these extra people and so we
started working with uh Justin Wy who at
the time was going under the name uh
cold
bones uh and we had performed at a
couple uh different hip-hop shows with
him way back in the day back in like
2014 2015 we did a few shows at the
hawth with him and I remember seeing him
I'm like this kid spit like this kid's
dope you know he's really cool so I
always kind of had him on my radar
anyway and then um and then uh we had
each other on Facebook for a while or
whatnot but I remember there was uh at
some point um he had made this post and
he was like Hey like I'm putting on the
final touches on this EP that I've been
working on for a while I need one more
guest feature who wants to get on it and
I like came in I was like
sup talk to uh I was like what's up like
yeah let's do it uh and so we were going
to do this song together and so and that
was actually before I moved to Minnesota
back in
2018 uh summer of 2018 I moved to
Minnesota for about a year uh but before
I left uh I got into the studio with
this kid and we did this song together
and then we had also performed a show
together um where I got on it was his
show uh and he asked me to come on and
do the song that I was featured on with
him uh and so I did that and that's kind
of how I knew him uh like that's where
we really kind of got to know each other
personally and then I left to Minnesota
and I came back for the show that we did
the rap battle at and that same weekend
I made a music video for cold bones for
Justin Wy and it was a remix to one of
his songs uh that I put a verse on as
well to glow up so the first song we did
together was called disco spaceand by
Cold bones and dopamine uh and then the
second one was the glowup remix uh also
featuring me and so uh I made the music
video for that song while I was out here
for a few days and then I went back to
Minnesota uh and so we I had him on that
show I believe um I talked Ryan into
putting him on that show and he put on
such a killer performance that we were
just like dude we [__] with this kid and
so we kept asking him to come back uh to
more of our shows and uh like he's got
this really super dope kind of like
party VI like all of his stuff is really
fun it's super fun to listen to like you
know he's got really cool flows really
really crispy type of a style like he's
a badass like he's he's a cool little
kid uh and so uh he he's done he's done
a bunch of shows with us and um then
roulette Delgado uh roulette Delgado
came on the first time with the DOR
Becker show and actually we did a cipher
a whole Half-Life ENT Cipher where it
was me Ryan Giannis and then we had
roulette and Justin on there and then
Carissa Ryan's girlfriend she filmed it
uh she filmed on YouTube yeah and that's
on YouTube uh you can find us at
halflife entertainment that's HF no l in
there halflife entertainment uh anyway
so that Cipher was the first time we had
all worked together on like one thing
together as like a whole te so they
weren't even a part of halflife
entertainment just yet but we had the
DOR Becker show coming up and so was it
the DOR Becker show yeah yeah it was the
DOR Becker show yeah yeah yeah yeah uh
we had the DOR Becker show coming up and
so we were like we're going to get all
these artists to perform on one Cipher
real quick you know because we had
chosen them for this show and so we
decided to do the cipher just everybody
that's on this show has also got one
song together like that's cool that's
awesome you know uh and so that was the
first time we all worked together that
was the first time I met roulette
Delgado uh and then he did the show for
us and he has such an incredible story
um man has been through a lot he's he's
is he more R&B yeah so he well he's a
he's a rap He will wrap your [__]
face off dude this dude will rip you
apart when it comes to that but he is
also yeah his his style on R&B and
singing is [__] amazing what is what
genra is does he consider himself as I
would say it's probably R&B soul in
hip-hop it's urban
Urban Soul Urban Soul there you go there
Urban Soul so hard with genre but it's
definitely like it's definitely R&B
because I you you pick up so many Vibes
of like really popular R&B songs from
like early 2000s and things like that
some Neo some Usher you just got got
that rapper lyric like to where it's
like when you're listening to like a
rapper rap you're listening to what the
words they're saying he pulls you in
with that even oh he's got a story man
he has got a story the man has been
through so much and and I think that's
what really drew me to him first he had
a really dope verse on the cipher but
then we did the show and he told the
story in between each song and he did
this you know the way he did it where
like he would talk about himself and
kind of give a background to what he was
about to sing and then he would sing
this song with like the music video for
a playing behind it know it was amazing
he put on this incredible performance
and I was just like holy [__] I didn't
know it was yeah like like he just he
inspires the hell out of me that guy
like and his level of talent is just un
unmatched unmatch he like he's he's one
of the Portland artist that more people
know of than most of the other guys and
he deserves every bit of it he was able
to do the Mota Center in front of 19,000
people and he deserved every single
minute of it he is an incredible person
he's a champion for the lgbtq community
I hope I said that right lgbtq I A plus
I a yeah okay yes that one I sorry mean
dis be disrespectful but uh he he's a
champion for that he's he's very very
open about it he did the Moto Center
with a rainbow flag around his neck you
know uh and he just promotes love he
promotes PE positivity he is an
incredible artist definitely somebody
you guys got to check out roulette
Delgato uh and then finally there is
Karissa cardinas and she is also hope I
said that last name right she is uh
Ryan's girlfriend and she is one of the
most talented and incredible singers
you've ever heard her her voice is so
[__] powerful you hear her just
busted you're like what she was I know
it's a typical sentence but she was such
a ball of nerves before she did her
first one and she was and it was like
once you started going I'm like oh my
God what are you nervous for it's it's
crazy is the typical thing of course we
heard her for you know like years before
before she got on stage with it and I
was always just like dude like for me
personally I I've said it before I'll
say it again I think she's one of the
most talented members of halflife
entertainment you know like she has she
doesn't have a whole lot of songs out
she hasn't done a whole lot of live
performances but her Talent is is there
I feel like like she was I feel like she
was born with it honestly like she like
she starts to sing on some and you're
just like [__] you're just in I want to
in the future there's a couple ideas
that I have I one time we were down here
oh is it when we first that podcast I
remember I walked down here and y'all
were just like goofing off and hanging
out and like having drinks and hanging
out down here and uh and Ryan and his
girlfriend were playing it was like they
started singing like Jay-Z and Beyonce
or some [__] together and I was like
what is happening this is so dope I was
like it was this moment where I walked
in and they're like doing this cover and
her voice sounds good and and Ryan's
going on the piano you guys are just
having a good time they they have they
have a song together they've done it
they've uh they've done it a few times
live but they have a song together that
they do they have three songs have they
how much of them have they done together
like on stage though they've done three
on stage oh they've done three on stage
none of them are out none of yeah none
of these songs are out but they do have
music they have like an entire whatever
they do music video wise for those it's
G to be awesome I I definitely think
they will and I definitely think they
should because you know that's such a
power couple move you know the the dude
can like he's producing all the music
that she can sing on uh and then just
lacing them with some bars you know so
they're they're a fantastic
and you could see that eny
each I think Carissa I think I think she
kind of like you know I think I think
her being a part of Ryan's life has like
brought a lot out of him uh and I think
it's like it's definitely made him a
better person uh and you know a much
better like uh artist and businessman
you know and I think I I think they they
can build off of each other absolutely
100% And I think that's so dope and you
know I I'll see I'm with them hanging
out with them or like seeing pictures I
get like how y'all just have how you
just how you just get into a
relationship where you both want the
same thing and you this is a like what
ah why why not me you this this is
awesome you know like so they they
they're they're incredible I love them
to death um and she's she is an amazing
artist and and I think she's also just
as a person she's a really dope ass
person who is she's really motherly
especially when it comes to everybody
else uh on on halflife entertainment and
she you know she kind of She Keeps Us
straight she keeps her opinions in there
she's really really good about making
sure that you know like if she's not
down with it she's going to let you know
that she's not down with it or what not
like she the grou probably needs that
more than anything absolutely dude she's
yeah so like her her and Ryan are just a
like you know an awesome awesome power
couple and and and uh I think yeah when
Ryan came to me in I think it was like
August or September of last year and he
was like I want Justin roulette and
Karissa to be a part of halflife
entertainment officially you know I was
I was like yes there's no like
hesitation no argument no anything I
have so much love for each one of these
people um I have so much respect for
each of these people there Artistry is
amazing it's incredible and it inspires
me it motivates me and you know now I'm
responsible for creating the visuals to
all their audio work you know and that's
that's such a phenomenal like feeling
and responsibility and knowing that like
so far between roulette uh between
Justin and I've made music videos for
Ryan Reed as well like when they get it
and they're just like [__] yes this
right here you know like so I you know I
know I did something that uh they wanted
but they weren't expecting you know and
a lot of times that's how it comes out
like they they weren't expecting for it
to show up look look look look like that
you know and so like having that to be
an artist as and especially the new just
wild video just wild St kid check that
video out but he let me play uh he let
me kind of take free reign W with that
one you know he he had some ideas where
he was like I want to get shot here shot
here shot here and whatnot and then I
was like all right let's do what if we
did like a poker game and he's like a
poker game and I was like yeah let's I
I'm listening to the song I see a poker
game let's do a [__] poker game dude
and he's like yeah let's do it you know
and it ended up being like the most
prominent part of the music video you
know and then and then I went in and I
just kind of like my music video style
is like really like
fast it's kind of like it fits the
groove of the song a lot you know so if
it's a high energy song It's a high
energy video video got a lot of like
crazy effects happening and things like
that and uh you know Justin was you know
he he was he was gracious enough to just
be like yeah dud just kind of go off do
what you want to do you know and just
let me play with it you know and it's
like it's a learning process for me
because I haven't there's a lot of [__]
on it the way it came out that I've
never done before but I was able to do
it with this one you know and and it's
and that video came out so awesome I
definitely think it's probably my best
video to date for sure um and then the
no explanation video is coming and
that's just yeah we've talked about that
already so well so one thing I was just
thinking I was just thinking about the
other like artist podcast that I've done
I was like oh why did I ask them did you
teach yourself all of this [__] yeah oh
absolutely was I took I was like
mentioning that because I feel like we
forget like sometimes when we teach
ourselves a bunch of stuff like oh yeah
dude and and and you know what I think
it's so important to let people know
that because like it it opens the door
for people to know that like this is not
impossible to do this is like this is
all selftaught you know I
took two video classes in high school
okay for like a semester each and that's
it that that's that's the extent of my
knowledge for video around then too was
kind of like you probably didn't learn a
ton that no oh no I didn't I didn't
learn [__] majority of the stuff I
learned and majority of the things that
I pick up on and get like really good at
if I can't learn it by just doing it
YouTube YouTube teaches me everything
YouTube you can learn everything on it
so like you know it bothers me when
people are just like man I wish I could
do that I wish I could do this well [__]
why don't you yeah dude it's funny you
look at my episodes like all the people
I've had so far that are starting
businesses and stuff i' I always ask him
like what's going on and it's like oh
you went to school for this right no no
YouTube everybody's just
exactly why waste time money when you
could you could learn it right there and
then just the rest of it is just for me
especially is like you know to learn
little tips and tricks on you know
things I could do with my music things I
can do with my videos and whatnot and
then I just go and personalize them and
then just add my own little flares to
them or whatnot exactly like and you
won't do it like you won't be able to
see what it looks like until you try it
right and so like I've put
out way too many terrible [__] videos
to be like that I I don't even want to
think like it just gives me anxiety to
think about stresses me out you know but
now the stuff that I'm putting out I'm
proud of and I want you to watch it and
I want you love it you know like you
know what I hope I hope that in 10 years
you think that these videos are terrible
because you've gotten so much better
that's what I hope for you I feel like
it's going to Happ you guys just like
keep improving and you keep doing it
that's what I love about your whole crew
obviously you especially it's like like
just going full board with these things
like you're not waiting for people to
give you permission you're not waiting
for like uh well not always the approval
even it's just like I'm going to pick
this thing up and I'm going to do it I'm
going nobody's gonna do it for me yeah
dude it's something that like I I talk
about with h when I started DJing I was
like man there's nowhere I can play
Electronic Music and that's all I'm
listening to that's all I want to DJ I
don't want to DJ like hip-hop and stuff
when it first started it was just EDM
EDM EDM dubstep like all I could get I
just loved it house music um and so I
was like [__] it dude I'm going to throw
my own parties like I don't want to play
for other people's I don't want to play
whatever people want me to do and so I
started throwing those Renegade parties
I don't know if you guys ever went to
any of those I actually never was
invited to any of those they were they
were very like Warehouse ravy like you
got the address if you were like but
sometimes get out there we' get like 500
people out there that's awesome it was
insane but but it's what I did and it's
like I didn't realize I was doing it
back then but I was kind of like well
[__] if nobody else is going to put me
on I'm going to put myself on and that
is what all of you guys have been doing
since day one and it's very
inspirational and man thinking forward
into 20 years if you guys just keep
working as hard as you always work I'm
excited um I hope we're all still
friends at that point and I could just
be alongside you helping out in any way
like vice versa absolutely dud I just I
I'm in a very this place in my life I
have a lot of often moments of like very
outside perspective of like this is a
moment in my life like I'm going to be
live to be however many years old and at
this moment in my life I'm appreciating
this and it's just cool to think of like
it's likely to think that the following
years the musicians you hang out with
we're just going to keep getting better
in our certain ways we're going to keep
making videos and keep trying things
like comedy and trying things like
writing and all these things it's just
interesting and exciting to think about
the coming life for for musicians in our
area and people that we know you know
yeah absolutely absolutely man um so
we're we're getting fairly up here in
time um let's close this out with right
now exactly right now if we all got
amber alerts on all three of our phones
and it's like yo you guys have three
hours until for sure you're going to
have to fist fight zombies at your front
door what's our move right [__] now
like Amber Alert it's like this is no
joke and it's enough to where we believe
it we're like damn we gota we got to do
something what do we do help me out bro
keep me alive what we do uh [__] man I
would probably have us uh go and Rob
like a gun store go to Jason get a bunch
W my Uncle Jason has a lot of guns you
got Uncle Jason in the area I got an
Uncle J he's in reer he's up in reer so
we can get there we got we might even
get away from the zombies might be able
to buy us some more time this is
honestly okay so here's a secret of this
podcast or do you have like
sledgehammers like rakes and things like
that we could [__] them up just like
that I mean I have like a long I have a
leaf blower I really like to Blow The
Leaf you know what if we like get like a
baseball bat okay and then just have
like the get in the car and then just
two dudes on either side of the window
just hanging out this is so plausible
and his music video footage BR that's
exactly dude that's music whoever isn't
driving we always have one person in the
backseat they're writing lyrics whatever
we're doing it's like hey bro it's your
job to write the lyrics this time like
we're going to go hunt zombies write
what you're feeling and we're like we
know we're going to get through this
artist how do you feel about this this
moment right now how does this zombie
make you feel exactly dude yeah so I
would I feel like we could I feel like
we could we could make we could do some
damage to some zombies like we
definitely could and if we need to we
can go to your uncle Jason's I'm just
making these connections that's why I
have this podcast man I'm really just
trying to make connections I see a
zombie outbreak coming up or trying to
like who's your uncle who's your uncle
so I have like thoughts on a m he knows
how to make semi-automatic weapons into
full automatic weapons like he's he's G
so don't snitch on I'm not I'm not I'm
not trying to incriminate anybody I'm
saying I'm not saying he does I'm saying
he knows how to pict I'm picturing Bert
from Tremors you guys ever see Tremors
that movie I actually have not oh man
it's it's super funny but he's just like
this guy who who's held up in his he has
like a little cave down there and you
open the the thing and he's got it all
on the wall guns on the wall and it's
all safe I just know I I just know if
anybody's everever going to be fully
prepared for a zombie outbreak when it
happens is going to be Uncle Jay all
right Uncle Jay that's where we're going
that's my guy all right bro one more
time let everybody know where they can
find you um your info where they can
check you out uh my name is Max V you
can find me on Facebook uh maxv just
maxv pain Max with two x's uh I'm on
Instagram maxv pain uh you can also
follow the uh the new coil and pain
Instagram and Facebook pages Instagram
is official coil pain uh you could also
find the coil and pain page on Facebook
with that same URL um other than that
you know if you see our
videos follow us subscribe to our
YouTube Pages because they're about to
get crazier they're about to get better
and there's going to be so much more of
them and you know we're they're very in
depth they're enjoyable to watch like
all of it like oh like this is what
these guys think you know I was watching
quite a few videos this point like you
guys thank you thank you very much thank
you for having me on yeah I'm really
easy to find it's it's maxv pain or
official coil pain anywhere and
everywhere uh the EP is coming out here
in a few months it's uh it's incredible
it's almost done our new song is out
right now on Spotify check us out have a
fun time uh I yeah I don't I don't think
I have a whole lot less to say man thank
you so much for having me on this has
been great this been an awesome
conversation I'm I'm glad that you came
thank you guys for coming by um I'm
always happy to to chill and then I I'm
glad that you allow me to like I was
like hey man we got to talk about comedy
and Society so thanks forks for off that
ledge with me a little bit um uh man Ju
Just as a um outside of this podcast as
a Creator sort of musician whatever I am
I appreciate what you're doing as a
comedian and musician I appreciate what
you're doing too man this between the
podcast and your own music and
everything like that it's it's awesome
and it's it's motivating for me oh yeah
and and this podcast itself is you know
the episodes that I've listened to like
I said they've they've consistently been
benefiting me in some way you know like
I just I hear things and I latch on to
them and I'm like I could I could apply
that I could do that I could have that
as a part of my life and so you know
what's happening on here is amazing it's
incredible uh you know we didn't have
too much depth on like you know mental
health or anything like that but at
least you know if people find some
inspiration in thinking about the
creative process and things like that
because that's what helped me out of my
darkest times you know just being able
to stay creative that's that's a lot of
the the uh you know I don't want to
overuse this word because it's excites
me but the Trojan Horse of a lot of what
I'm doing here is like some people might
not see it at first as a mental health
podcast of course my demeanor and I have
little tips and tricks that I throw out
but I think that persuing your joy and
uh following your dreams and and
listening to your intuition and doing
what you think you you need to and and
bringing people around you that that
feel the same way is a lot of the way to
to fight depression to to and to learn
about things and gain knowledge about
your depression or about even just
things that interest you rather than
just learning about terrible things or
or feeling your depression being a
victim of it it it helps I think
knowledge is power in so many ways
essentially it is you know i' like one
one of the things that's really
important for me is just learning how to
get better how to be better and just you
know even if I'm not like actively
trying to be like let me not be
depressed let me do things that big me
like even if I'm just working on myself
as a person as a human being is you know
checking the way I think about things
checking the way that I perceive things
you know if I I feel that I'm working on
those things and that they're getting
better that in itself just pulls me out
of the SL slump and out of that that
that dark hole just knowing that you
know as a person I've improved in this
area this area this area I still feel
like [__] but at least you know I look
good I feel good I feel better you know
like yeah you got to take your WIS and
like okay I am doing good in that area
exactly yeah and that's something I
neglect to do a lot of the time and and
so I spend a lot of time just being
really down on myself and being super
critical on myself and then you know
there comes a point or a time where you
just you're able to step back and look
and it's like wow I've I've actually
come a really long way like this is
incredible you know this is amazing and
you know I don't do that nearly as much
as I should uh but it helps a lot it
helps a lot to just be able to step back
and be like I've actually progressed
I've actually made forward steps and
that in itself is something that helps
you out so right that's that's that
would be my tip I love that dude Max vay
I appreciate you I appreciate you taking
care of yourself so you're here and and
having these conversations with me and
and I'm just I'm glad I'm on your guys'
team I'm glad I'm you know so glad that
you're a part we all part of this
together all of these creators in our
area we're not trying to do some versus
thing I just I'm I'm glad to be floating
along with yall oh yeah man thank you so
much yeah fist bump me listeners
listeners quick little uh wedge in your
life here before this thing progresses
to another podcast whether it's mine
whether it's anybody's whether it's some
YouTube video any more entertainment
that you're listening to just throw a
wedge in it take a break take a quick
breath take a look around look at your
environment is what you're doing
matching up with who you want to be Tim
timately are you working towards your
your end goals of who you want to be
with this wonderful life take a look
around love yourself have a good rest of
your day